# PETR KOVAR

#### PERSONAL DETAILS

Email: pmkovar@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/pmkovar
Technical blog: blogs.gnome.org/pmkovar/

GitHub: github.com/pmkovar/

CV source code: github.com/pmkovar/pmkovar.github.io

#### **SUMMARY**

My expertise lies in technical communication, and project and program management, with a focus on delivering clear, effective documentation. I'm experienced in community management and open source software development, where I engage and connect both the community and corporate contributors.

Additionally, I'm skilled in technical translation, working within open source translation communities to make software and documentation accessible worldwide.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### 8/2018–9/2023 **Documentation Program Manager, Red Hat**

Brno, Czechia

- Reintegrated a writing group for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization, transforming it into an agile team.
- Developed new workflows for the team, mentored team members, including writers and project managers, to help them succeed in the new agile-driven environment.
- Responsible for release management, and task planning and tracking.
- Integrated various cloud native products into an umbrella Jira-centered project encompassing the broad area of OpenShift developer tools. This included DevOps, monitoring, logging, and cloud IDE Eclipse Che.
- ullet Project Management  $\cdot$  Program Management  $\cdot$  Agile & Waterfall Methodologies  $\cdot$  Jira

#### 3/2015-8/2018

#### Senior Technical Writer, Red Hat

Brno, Czechia

- Developed content strategy for single-sourcing desktop and OpenStack documentation to be delivered in both community and enterprise products.
- Worked on transforming CloudForms content into topic-based documentation using a new docs-as-code toolchain based on Asciidoc.
- $\bullet \ \ \textit{Content Strategy} \cdot \textit{Topic-based Authoring} \cdot \textit{AsciiDoc} \cdot \textit{Sphinx}$

### 4/2011-3/2015

### **Technical Writer II**

Brno, Czechia

- Developed content for broad areas of Linux platform and cloud products, including package, identity and access management, and desktop on Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
- Acted as a docs lead for the desktop documentation area, establishing single source workflows and engaging the GNOME and Fedora documentation and translation communities.
- $Linux \cdot DocBook \cdot XML \cdot Technical \ Writing \cdot Bash \cdot Git \cdot Single \ Sourcing \cdot Content \ Management$

## **PROJECTS**

#### 8/2017-3/2019

#### Documentation Project Team Lead, OpenStack

- Elected Project Team Lead of the OpenStack Documentation Project by the OpenStack community.
- Responsible for documentation release management, community engagement, writers mentorship. Represented the documentation project by running documentation sessions at the OpenStack summits and Project Team Gatherings.
- · As a writer, maintained Red Hat-specific content provided by the OpenStack Documentation Project.
- Collaborated on maintaining and building the OpenStack documentation site.
- Co-maintained the RDO project site.
- $\bullet \ \textit{Coaching \& Mentoring} \cdot \textit{Release Management} \cdot \textit{Community Management} \cdot \textit{Community Engagement}$

8/2017–Present

## Lead, GNOME Documentation Project

4/2010–Present

Member of the GNOME Translation Project Coordination Team, GNOME

2007-3/2018

**Czech Translation Team Coordinator, GNOME Translation Project** 

# **EDUCATION**

2015–2018 Masaryk University

Brno, Czechia

• Bachelor of Arts — BA, Information and Library Studies

# **CERTIFICATES**

• Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA), issued 9/2012

# LANGUAGES

- English full professional proficiency
- Czech native proficiency